The elephant in the room that, you know,
Trump and and Bent are wrestling with is
that, you know, we really look like an
emerging market economy. I mean, we've
got we've got a weak, arguably a weak
stock market as our economy slows down.
We've got a weak bond market as fewer
and fewer people trust our government to
do the responsible thing regarding
printing money. And we've got enormous
and growing deficits in spite of the
best efforts of Doge. And so, I think
when you look at those three things,
that's what happens when you have, you
know, a sovereign debt crisis, an
emerging market currency. Um, we've also
got the dollar. I mean, the thing we
haven't mentioned that I think is really
important, I'm sure Craig is focused on
it as well. We also got the dollar off a
lot. The dollar is 109 at the end of the
year. It's down to 99 now. That's a big
move. 10% in one quarter. And so, if
you're, you know, and a lot of the money
that was in our market is foreign money.
I mean, there's a net I don't know what
is it, Greg, $12 trillion of foreign
investment in our in our equity markets.
And it could be larger than that. But,
but but the bottom line is, you know,
the equity markets are down. They were
down at one point, you know, 10, 15,
20%. they bounce back a bit. Um, but you
know, you get a you get a declining
market and then you get a weaker dollar
and suddenly, you know, these people are
losing both ways because when they
convert back to their home currency, you
know, they've got the say say the
market's down 10% and say the dollar's
down 10%. Well, that means they they're
taking a 20% loss in their own currency.
And so, you know, that kind of becomes
reflexive where they think, well, gee,
should I if that trend continues, do I
really want to be in dollar-based
assets, you know, in the United States?
I think the answer is no. And so, you
know, my my great concern, what I'm
watching, I mean, I'm watching all these
things like a hawk, but the one that's
most interesting to me right now is the
stock market. You know, can the can the
stock market find its feet and start to
hang in around here or start to climb?
Um, I I think I'm I'm skeptical. You're
skeptical? Count me count me as they
they broke the glass and the mark the
economy is slowing down. The earnings
estimates are all going to have to be
revised downward. And as they're revised
downward, this is a market that was
priced perfect perfection. very happy
with Trump and I think you know reality
is going to be you know it's despite his
best efforts Trump is not going to be
able to deliver everything promised and
as the market comes to realize that it's
going to it's going to not like it and
the equity market's going to go down
when the equity market goes down that
makes people poor it slows the economy
down further that becomes reflexive I
mean to me this is a bubble very much
like it was the everything bubble it was
very much like the 2020 bubble or and
the 28 bubble and the 2000 bubble and
when bubbles burst they tend to go back
to their base level. And you know, I
mean, Husman says we'd have to go down
65%. For, you know, the the stocks, the
general stock market to enter the range
of quote unquote normal valuations.
Well, think about what a 65% decline in
the stock market would do to this
country. I mean, you know, the top 10%
of the country owns 84% of the bonds
since told us this or stocks and they
also account for 50% of the spending.
So, if you tell everybody who's in the
in that cohort that their retirement
account just got cut in half, guess
what? They're not going to buy cars,
they're not going to renovate the house,
they're not going to travel, they're not
going to eat out, they're not going to
do all kinds of things. And so, you
know, Benton and Trump are thinking to
themselves, well, this is okay. I mean,
the stock market goes down. Those aren't
the guys who voted for us. We, you know,
we wanted the middle class. We got them
and they voted us in, you know, and I
mean, the average guy doesn't own
stocks. The average American doesn't own
stocks. And so, stock market goes down.
That's not a big deal to him. But you
know when it becomes a big deal to him
when the plant that he works for has
less demand. Yeah. And he loses his job.
And so, you know, sadly, you know, in
trying to fix all this, doing the right
things, I mean, this could, you know,
this could really turn the politics
against these guys in two years and then
even worse in four years. Yeah. And
that's what I fear. Yeah. Look, we've
we've talked about this for for years,
right? That we've been, you know,
America's been overspending, over
consuming.
um stock market has been over earning,
margins have been too high, the money
printing has run rampant, right? And so
eventually um we would come back to some
sort of reality or one would be imposed
on us. And so if you had like maybe a
continuation of the the Biden administr,
you know, Biden 2.0 or Harris, whatever,
we would have just maybe continued along
the same path of deficit spending and
strong stock market and tech
outperformance and US exceptionalism
perhaps. Um but eventually we it would
lead to a you know such grotesque even
more grotesque wealth inequality that
the 99% would eventually rise up and you
know burn the whole thing down. And so
Trump comes in with the idea that well
we're not going to we have to we have to
do something uh eventually. Let's let's
do it now. Let's do it on our own terms
where we still have more control over
it. But I think they're quickly
realizing that this everything bubble as
it starts to unravel can unravel really
fast because the money printing has been
so excessive for so long. And so you've
you have all these things going on at
once. We've hollowed out the
manufacturing trust. We're trying to
bring it back. The deficits are out of
control. The stock market's overvalued.
We've had, you know, the the US equity
market capitalization is 65% of global
equity market capitalization versus, you
know, GDP and the 20%. So we we've we've
attracted all this capital. Now it's all
going the other way. We've lost we we're
we're losing trust with foreigners. So,
and once you once you lose the trust, it
never it really never comes back. And
so, you're going to have this outflow of
capital from the US from US assets.
Trump's going to try to encourage those
companies to invest domestically in
plants and equipment, which he'll have
some success, right? Hyundai's putting a
plant here. Honda's putting a plant
here. TMC's putting a plant here. That's
right. Yeah. TSM's putting a plant here.
Um, but Samsung, but it's harder to get
them to to do that when you when you
treat their money like Well, and
even even saying that they're going to
do that, you know, as as you and I know,
saying you're going to do a plant here
and actually spending the money to have
the plant here, it's a multi-year thing.
And so, you know, I mean, I I'm accused
of being a doomster, but I I got to tell
you, the macroeconomic outlook from my
point of view is really really bleak.
[Music]